documentary.org 2019-11-30

# Privacy Policy | International Documentary Association

### Introduction

This Privacy Notice explains how International Documentary Association collects and processes your Personal Data. Each time you use our Site, the current version of the Privacy Notice will apply. Accordingly, whenever you use our Site, you should check the date of this Privacy Notice and review any changes since the last version. This Privacy Notice is applicable to all Site visitors, registered users, and all other users of our Site. “Personal Data” is any information that enables us to identify you, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as your name, identification number, location data, online identifier or one or more factors specific to your physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. By visiting documentary.org,  the “Site”, you acknowledge that you have read and understood the processes and policies referred to in this Privacy Notice.

### Who we are

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), the Data Controller is International Documentary Association registered in the United States with a registered address at 3470 Wilshire Blvd., Suite 980, Los Angeles, CA 90010 USA.

### How to contact us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Notice, please contact us using the Contact Us section on our Site.

* * *

### How we collect personal data

We may collect and process the following Personal Data:

  * Contact information

  * Membership information

  * Due payment information

  * Purchase information

With regard to each of your visits to the Site, we do not automatically collect information unless provided by the visitor.

### How we collect non-personal data

We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your web browser and we may use this information to generate aggregate statistics about visitors to our Site, including, without limitation:

  * IP addresses

  * Browser type and plug-in details

  * Device type (e.g., desktop, laptop, tablet, phone, etc.)

  * Operating system

  * Local time zone

We may use non-Personal Data for various business purposes such as providing customer service, market research, and improving our Site. Please check your web browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings. 

### When do we collect information

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form or enter information on our site.

### How do we use your information

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize user's experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.

  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.

  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.

  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

  * To quickly process your transactions.

  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

### Cookies

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

Like many websites, our Site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of the Site. This helps us to analyze the use of the Site to customize and improve the content and the layout of the Site. When you first access the Site, you will receive a message advising you that cookies are in use. By continuing to browse the Site, you agree to our use of cookies as described in this Privacy Notice. You do not have to accept our cookies and can block them by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse all or some cookies. You may also delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of the Site that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer, if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use the following cookies:**

  * Functionality cookies

  * Google Universal Analytics

**We use cookies to:**

  * Help remember and process the items in the shopping cart.

  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.

  * Keep track of advertisements.

  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

**If users disable cookies in their browser:**

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It will turn off some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place orders.

### “Do not track” signals 

We support “do not track” signals (“DNT”). If you have DNT enabled in your web browser, we will not receive browser-related information from our advertising partners for tailoring advertisements. [IF THE ORGANIZATION DOES NOT RESPOND TO “DO NOT TRACK” SIGNALS] We do not respond to web browser “do not track” signals. As such, your navigation of our Site may be tracked as part of the gathering of quantitative user information described above. If you arrive at our Site by way of a link from a third party site that does respond to “do not track” requests, the recognition of any “do not track” request you have initiated will end as soon as you reach our Site. 

### How we use your personal data 

We will only process your Personal Data, where (1) you have provided your consent which can be withdrawn at any time, (2) the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party, (3) we are required by law, (4) processing is required to protect your vital interests or those of another person, or (5) processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate commercial interests, except where such interests are overridden by your rights and interests We may use Personal Data for the following purposes:

**Personal Data you give to us:**

  * to carry out our obligations arising from your membership, or any other contract entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and membership services that you request from us;

  * to organize events that you have purchased or registered for, and to provide you with information, and other materials, relating to the content of the event, the speakers, sponsors and other attendees;

  * to provide our newsletters and publications, provided you have given your consent;

  * to respond to your questions and provide related membership services;

  * to provide you with information about other events, products and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased, provided you have not opted-out of receiving that information

  * to provide you, or permit selected third parties to provide you, with information about events, products or services we feel may interest you, provided you have given your consent;

  * to notify you about changes to our membership service;

  * and to ensure that content from our Site is presented most effectively for you and your computer.

**Information we collect about you:**

  * to administer our Site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes

  * to improve our Site to ensure that content is presented most effectively for you and your computer

* * *

### Security and Storage

**How do we protect visitor information?**

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

**How long we store your personal data  **

We will store your Personal Data, in a form which permits us to identify you, for no longer than is necessary for the purpose for which the Personal Data is processed. We may retain and use your Personal Data as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements and rights, or if it is not technically reasonably feasible to remove it. Consistent with these requirements, we will try to delete your Personal Data quickly upon request. 

**How long we retain your personal data  **

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with our Site. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you service, contact us at [website@documentary.org](mailto:website@documentary.org). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's [Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en). They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. We have _not_ enabled Google AdSense on our site but we may do so in the future.

* * *

### California Online Privacy Protection Act (CalOPPA)

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. [Click here](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf) to learn more.

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

  * Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing us

  * By calling us

  * By logging in to their account

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**

It's also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking

* * *

### COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under the age of 13. If we learn that Personal Data of persons less than 13 years-of-age has been collected through our Site, we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.

* * *

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

 **In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via email within 7 business days.

We will notify the users via in site notification within 7 business days.

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

* * *

### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

 **We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders

  * We may also send you additional information related to your product and/or service.

  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred

**To be accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

  * NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses

  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way

  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters

  * Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.

  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly

  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can**

  * Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.

* * *

### General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

GDPR is a regulation that requires businesses to protect the personal data and privacy of EU citizens for transactions that occur within EU member states. [Click here](https://www.eugdpr.org/) to learn more.

For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), the Data Controller is International Documentary Association registered in Los Angeles with a registered address at 3470 Wilshire Blvd., Suite 980  
Los Angeles, CA 90010.

**Transfer of personal data outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) and international users**

We will not transfer Personal Data, relating to individuals within the European Economic Area (“EEA”), to third parties (i.e., those outside of our group), located outside of the EEA without ensuring adequate protection under European law.

We are headquartered in the United States. Your Personal Data may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, partners, merchants, or service providers who are located worldwide. If you are visiting our Site from outside the United States, be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located, and our central database is operated. By using our Service, you consent to any transfer of this information. 

* * *

### Your rights 

**Correction and removal**

If any of the information that we have about you is incorrect, or you wish to have information (including Personal Data) removed from our records, please contact us at [membership@documentary.org](mailto:membership@documentary.org).

**Opting Out**

Additionally, if you prefer not to receive marketing messages from us, please let us know by clicking on the unsubscribe link within any marketing message that you receive, or by sending a message to us at [admin@documentary.org](mailto:admin@documentary.org). 

**Your European Rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your Personal Data) if we intend to use your Personal Data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your Personal Data. You can also exercise the right by contacting us using the Contact Us section on our Site.

Under European data protection law, in certain circumstances, you have the right to:

  * Request access to your Personal Data

  * Request correction of your Personal Data

  * Request erasure of your Personal Data

  * Object to processing of your Personal Data

  * Request restriction of processing your Personal Data

  * Request transfer of your Personal Data

  * Withdraw your consent

In addition, where you believe that International Documentary Association has not complied with its obligations under this Privacy Notice or European law, you have the right to make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority, such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office. You can exercise any of these rights by contacting us using the Contact Us section on our Site. 

**Your Californian Rights**

FOR RESIDENTS OF CALIFORNIA ONLY. Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code requires select businesses to disclose policies relating to the sharing of certain categories of your Personal Data with third parties. If you reside in California and have provided your Personal Data to Company, you may request information about our disclosures of certain categories of Personal data to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us at one of the following addresses: [info@documentary.org](mailto:info@documentary.org) or

IDA Attn: California Privacy Rights  
3470 Wilshire Blvd., Suite 980  
Los Angeles, CA 90010

* * *

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may [contact us](https://www.documentary.org/ida/contact-us).

_Last Updated: May 2018_
